ILGWU. David Dubinsky audio-visual recordings 5780/002 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. David Dubinsky audio-visual recordings
1956-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5780/002 AV
5.33 cubic feet
5 linear feet
Audio-visual recordings
This collection primarily contains audio recordings of David Dubinsky's speeches and other events attended by Dubinsky.
6849864
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
June 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, June 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
1892 Born February 22nd in Brest-Litovsk, then in Russia, son of Bezalel and Shaine Wishingrad Dobnievski. Moved to Lodz, where the family operated a bakery.
1903 Began to work in father's bakery after attending three terms in Hebrew Zionist school.
1907 Qualified as master baker and joined bakers' union, organized by the General Jewish Workers Union, the Bund. Served as secretary of the bakers' union. Arrested, together with 60 other members of the union, in the course of a strike; released after payment of 25 rubles by father. Left Lodz to live with an uncle in Brest-Litovsk; after three months returned to Lodz and rejoined the bakers' union.
1908 Arrested while attending an illegal meeting of the bakers and, as a second offender, exiled to a small Siberian village. Escaped and made his way to Chelyabinsk and from there to Lodz, working as a baker under an assumed name.
1910 Sailed, with an older brother, Chaira, to New York City.
1911 Arrived in NYC on January 1st. Lived on Lower East Side and became apprenticed to learn the cutter's craft. Accepted as a member of Local 10, Cutters' Union of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, on July 13th.
1914 Married Emma Goldberg, an undergarment operator and member of the ILGWU. (The couple had one child, a daughter, Jean.)
1918 Elected to executive board of Local 10.
1919 Elected vice-president of Local 10.
1920 Elected chairman of Local 10.
1921 Elected president of Local 10. Elected general manager (a new office combining duties of manager and secretary) of Local 10 in December.
1922 Elected vice president of ILGWU and member of General Executive Board.
1929 Elected General Secretary-Treasurer of ILGWU. Served as Acting President of ILGWU.
1932 Elected by GEB in June as President, following death of President Benjamin Schlesinger.
1934 Elected vice president of American Federation of Labor in October.
1935 Joined with John L. Lewis of Mine Workers and Sidney Hillman of Amalgamated Clothing Workers to form a Committee for Industrial Organization. First U.S. labor representative to the International Labor Organization.
1936. Joined in founding the American Labor Party in New York State. Served as Democratic Party elector for the ticket of Franklin D. Roosevelt and John N. Garner.
1944 Joined in founding Liberal Party.
1945 Elected vice president of American Federation of Labor.
1966 Offered resignation as President to GEB at meeting of March 14th, to take effect April 12th. Resignation effective June 15th, anniversary of date on which he was first elected President.
1982 Died in New York City on September 17, 1982.
Scope and Contents
This collection primarily contains audio recordings of David Dubinsky's speeches and other events attended by Dubinsky.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/002. ILGWU. David Dubinsky correspondence
5780/002 P. ILGWU. David Dubinsky photographs
5780/136. ILGWU. David Dubinsky scrapbooks
5780/179 MB. ILGWU. David Dubinsky memorabilia
5780/179 P. ILGWU. David Dubinsky photographs
General
"Permanent deposit"
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--United States.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
6849864
- [no title] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  7" audio reel.
- [no title] (Box 1, Folder 2)
- [no title] (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Italian-American Labor Council Twentieth Anniversary. Luigi Antonini, Toastmaster; David Dubinsky, Honored Guest, 1961? (Box 1, Folder 3a)
- [no title] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- [no title] (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Dubinksy, dinner, III, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  7" audio reel. November 3, 1966.
- [no title] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  7" reel.
- [no title] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  5' audio reel. Copy #1: poor beginning (not eq.) and poor end (slow), 8 db rise @ 5000', low cut at 150', speed varied
- "The Man Who Would Not Bargain" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  7" audio reel. Written and Directed by Pat Daniels; Narrated by Joseph Wiseman
- Public Hearing, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  7" audio reel. Recorded July 19, 1968.
- McClellan committee hearings, Hoffa, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  7" audio reel. 2 sides, August 23, 1957, p.m.
- Madison Square Garden, George Meany, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  7" audio reel. March 5, 1958.
- Italian-American Labor Council Twentieth Anniversary. Luigi Antonini, Toastmaster; David Dubinsky, Honored Guest (Box 1, Folder 15)
  7" audio reel; 1961?
- President's Report, G.E.B., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  7" audio reel. September 9, 1963.
- [no title] (Box 1, Folder 20c)
  7" audio reel. Reel No. A-635, #2 tape for air (total time approx 40 min) (Tape #3), 2:30 P.M. June 5, ends at marker, not used
- ILGWU Directors and Staff Dinner, #1 (Box 1a, Folder 21a)
  7" audio reel; 1964?
- ILGWU Directors and Staff Dinner, #2 (Box 1a, Folder 21b)
- ILGWU Directors and Staff Dinner #3, Union Health Center Celebration, 1964 (Box 1a, Folder 21c)
  7" audio reel. June 5, 1964.
- Tyler broadcast, Local 89, 1964 (Box 1a, Folder 22)
  5" audio reel. Running time: 8:52. September 5, 1964.
- Talk of New York, WCBS NY, ILGWU references, 1965 (Box 1a, Folder 23)
  7" audio reel. February 1, 1965.
- Dubinsky during dinner, I, 1966 (Box 1a, Folder 27)
- Dubinsky during dinner, II, 1966 (Box 1a, Folder 28)
- Liberal Party, Dubinsky program, 1968 (Box 1a, Folder 34)
  7" audio reel. Running time: 13:48. Monday, November 4, 1968.
- [no title] (Box 1b, Folder 1)
  Audiocassette
- D.D. [David Dubinsky?] C.J.B. {Chicago Joint Board?}, Staff Conference, C.J.B. Unity Weekend, Industrial and Political Review, Comments on problems in union—New directions in industrial merger; Linsey Campaign (Box 1b, Folder 2)
  7" audio reel
- David Dubinksy (LBJ), 1971 (Box 1b, Folder 3)
  Audiocassette. November 4, 1971.
- David Dubinsky interview (Box 1b, Folder 4)
  5" audio reel
- David Dubinsky, CJB,BA, Class opening, Astor, 1964 (Box 1b, Folder 5)
  5" audio reel. March 5, 1964
- Dub of Liberal Party, David Dubinksy, 1969 (Box 1b, Folder 6)
  5" audio reel. December 18, 1969
- Dubinksy, Liberal Party, 1969 (Box 1b, Folder 7)
  5" audio reel. Running time: 15:10. 1:00 P.M., November 2, 1969; 11:30 A.M., November 3, 1969.
- Dubinsky (Box 1b, Folder 8)
- Governor's Conference, 1970 (Box 1b, Folder 9)
  Audiocassette. Side 1: Governor's Conference on Aging, Introductory remarks Governor Rockefeller, David Dubinsky (award); Side 2: Continuation—remarks of David Dubinsky after receiving award of Senior Citizen of the Year. May 1, 1970.
- Italian-American Labor Council Twentieth Anniversary. Luigi Antonini, Toastmaster; David Dubinsky, Honored Guest (Box 1b, Folder 10)
- Liberal Party, Dubinsky program, 1968 (Box 1b, Folder 11)
  5" audio reel. Broadcast on November 4, 1968.
- Liberal Party, Dubinsky program, 1968 (Box 1b, Folder 12)
  5" audio reel. Broadcast on November 4, 1968 on WVED.
- [no title] (Box 1b, Folder 13)
  7" audio reel. Labelled "Local 10 meeting," with strikethrough
- President David Dubinsky, Speech at the Pankin Celebration, Saturday, March 27, 1965, from B. Tabachinsky, (file—confidential—no use) (Box 1b, Folder 14)
  5" audio reel. March 27, 1965.
- Public hearing, 1968 (Box 1b, Folder 15)
  7" audio reel. July 19, 1968.
- Radio speech about G.E.B. session of January 30, 1967, delivered on radio program of Jewish Labor Committee on February 25, 1967, by S. Weiss (Box 1b, Folder 16)
  5" audio reel. February 25, 1967.
- Reel No. 2, 9:15 meeting, Medical Workshop, June 5, 1964, first side: Intro by Louis Rolnick, David Dubinsky, Dr. Kaplan, Dr. Schiowitz; second side: Dr. Schiowitz, Dr. Rosenbloom, Dr. Stein, Dr. Newark (?) (Box 1b, Folder 17)
- Reel No. A-634 (Tape #2), 2:30 P.M., June 5, Air 9-9:30 P.M.; Chairman Mr. Nelson H. Cruikshank, Dr. Martin Cherkasky, Dr. Kenneth W. Clement, Dr. Caldwell B. Esselstyn, Dr. Russell V. Lee, Dr. Howard Rusk, including speech by Mr. Dubinsky, President of t (Box 1b, Folder 18)
- David Dubinsky address at local 60-60A installation of William Schwartz, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- David Dubinsky address at Pennsylvania meeting (Wilkes-Barre) correction, post 956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- President Dubinsky's TV address at meeting of National Board of Coat and Suit Industry, Miami Beach, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  March 2, 1966. Old label #37
- David Dubinsky statement on Daily Mirror editorial regarding ILGWU pension fund, Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  7" audio reel. May 15, 1956. Old label #57
- David Dubinsky acceptance address, Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  7" audio reel. May 18, 1956. Old label #60
- David Dubinsky address to Convention of United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers, Hotel Statler, New York City (incomplete), 1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  7" audio reel. June 3, 1956. Old label #61
- David Dubinsky—station WEVD, political broadcast, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  7" audio reel. Yiddish. November 4, 1956. Old label #62
- David Dubinsky—Dress Joint Board officers, Cloak Joint Board officers, Training Institute, ILGWU Building, regarding McClellan Committee, 2 parts, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  7" audio reel. April 5, 1957. Old label #63
- David Dubinsky—Balboa Theater, Canal Zone, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  7" audio reel. November 1958. Old label #64A
- David Dubinsky—United Auto Worker Convention, Atlantic City, New Jersey, regarding racketeering, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  7" audio reel. April 11, 1957. Old label #64A
- David Dubinsky—United Auto Workers Convention, Atlantic City, New Jersey, part 2, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  7" audio reel. April 11, 1957. Old label #64B
- David Dubinsky lecture to Training Institute class (Box 2, Folder 12)
  7" audio reel. Old label #65
- Dubinsky (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Show: Lib, Library No. 24210, Film Type 7388. Old label #66
- David Dubinsky address to New York Dressmakers at Madison Square Garden, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  7" audio reel. Starts at 63 rev. March 6, 1958. Old label #67
- David Dubinsky talk to New York officers after Israel trip, Park Sheraton Hotel, New York, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  7" audio reel. November 5, 1959. Old label #75
- Highstown, New Jersey (Box 3, Folder 1)
  9" film reel. Silent.
- Hugh Gaitskell, ILGWU Convention, Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  7" audio reel. Old label #58. May 17, 1956.
- Governor Munoz-Marin of Puerto Rico, ILGWU Convention, Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  7" audio reel. Old label #59. May 18, 1956.
- David Dubinsky anniversary, 25th anniversary, Madison Square Garden, New York City (Box 3, Folder 4)
  7" audio reel. Old label #66A. 2 sides. Side 1 starts: 33-473 concert, 485 speeches, 502 Nagler, 610 Antonini, cont. Antonini, 127 Intr. Mrs. R., 179 Intro. Mayor W., 313 Intr. Hochman, 415 intr. Judge Panken, 598 Intr. Pres. Meany
- David Dubinsky anniversary, 25th anniversary, Madison Square Garden, New York City (Box 3, Folder 5)
  7" audio reel. Old label #66B. 1 side, continue Meany, 56—Stulberg, 125-506—David Dubinsky
- Dressmakers' contract ratification meeting, Manhattan Center, New York City, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  7" audio reel. Old label #68A. March 11, 1957.
- Dressmakers' contract ratification meeting, Manhattan Center, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  7" audio reel. Old label #68B. March 11, 1957.
- Strike meeting, Pittston, Pennsylvania, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  7" audio reel. Old label #69A. April 15, 1958.
- Strike meeting, Pittston, Pennsylvania, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  7" audio reel. Old label #69B. April 15, 1958.
- David Dubinsky lecture, Training Institute class, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  7" audio reel. Old label #70. June 2, 1958.
- New York Dress Joint Board, Installation of General Manager Zimmerman, Hotel New Yorker, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  7" audio reel. Old label #70A. June 30, 1958.
- David Dubinsky address at National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board, Miami Beach, Florida, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  7" audio reel. Old label #71. Running time 46:00. February 4, 1959.
- David Dubinsky at Local 117 installation, Manhattan Center, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  7" audio reel. Old label #73. March 10, 1959.
- Local 10 Installation Meeting, Manhattan Center, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  7" audio reel. Old label #74. March 30, 1959.